Threads Supplemental Privacy Policy
===================================

Effective May 13, 2025
----------------------

Threads is provided by Meta Platforms Ireland Limited ("Meta", "we", "our" or "us") and is part of Instagram. You can use Threads by creating a profile with your Instagram account or, alternatively, with your email address or phone number, to share, view, and interact with content on the Threads app and website (“**Threads**”). You can also use Threads without a profile while still having access to Threads’ key functionality. Your use of Threads, with or without a profile, is governed by the [Threads Terms of Use](https://help.instagram.com/769983657850450?helpref=faq_content).

Threads integrates with third party services (“**Third Party Services**”) via an interoperable protocol, and is part of a network sometimes called the Fediverse. In the Fediverse, Threads users can share content with, view and interact with content from, follow, and be followed by people outside of Threads who use such Third Party Services (“**Third Party Users**”). To enable these interactions between Threads users and Third Party Users we share information about Threads users with Third Party Services, and collect and process information about Third Party Users, even if they don’t have an account on Threads or other Meta Products as described further below.

**At present, Threads is not interoperable with Third Party Services**, but interoperability will follow soon, and we’ll update this note, when this is ready. As such, information in this Threads Supplemental Privacy Policy describing what information we collect and how we use and share it when Threads is interoperable with Third Party Services, is not yet applicable.

The [Meta Privacy Policy](https://privacycenter.instagram.com/policy) describes the information we process to support the [Meta Products](https://privacycenter.instagram.com/policy/?annotations[0]=0.ex.0-WhatProductsDoesThis), including Threads. This Threads Supplemental Privacy Policy supplements the [Meta Privacy Policy](https://privacycenter.instagram.com/policy) by providing a detailed overview of the information that we collect, process and share to support Threads. It also describes how we collect, process and share information when Third Party Users interact with Threads and when Threads users interact with Third Party Users.

You can find links to helpful sections of the Meta Privacy Policy below, but we encourage you to also read all of the [Meta Privacy Policy](https://privacycenter.instagram.com/policy) to learn more about the information we collect, and how we use and share it on Meta Products. In addition, please see the [Meta Cookies Policy](https://privacycenter.instagram.com/policies/cookies/) for information regarding our use of cookies and other similar technologies.

What information do we collect?
-------------------------------

The [Meta Privacy Policy](https://privacycenter.instagram.com/policy) describes the information we collect under “What information do we collect?”. Below, please find additional detail regarding information we collect when you use or interact with Threads:

*   **Your Threads activity and information that you provide when you use Threads with a profile**:  
      
    We collect information you provide to us when you use or interact with Threads, including:
    
    *   **Threads Profile Information**: We collect the information you provide when you create your Threads profile, including your name, email address, and settings and preferences.
        
        *   **If you have created a Threads profile with your Instagram account**, some of your Threads profile information is provided from or managed by your Instagram account, such as your name and username. To change your Threads username, you must change your Instagram username. Learn more about [how to edit your profile on Threads](http://help.instagram.com/759628745637994?helpref=faq_content).
        
    *   **Threads Activity**: When you use Threads, we collect information about your activity on Threads, including the content you create, the types of content you view or interact with and how you interact with it, metadata about your content, the Threads features you use and how you use them, the hashtags you use, and the time, frequency, and duration of your activities on Threads. Learn more about activity information in the [Meta Privacy Policy](https://privacycenter.instagram.com/policy).
    *   **Threads Followers and Other Connections**: We collect information about followers, and other users and communities you’re connected to and interact with.
    
*   **Your Instagram activity and information that we collect when you create a Threads profile with your Instagram account:**  
      
    **If you have created a Threads profile with your Instagram account, we also collect and use information about your profile**, activity and followers and connections on Instagram. For example, we may suggest Threads profiles for you to follow if you already follow them on Instagram.  
      
    **If you have created a Threads profile with your email address or phone number** we won’t collect and use information from any Instagram accounts you might have to do things like personalise your Threads experience or recommendations, including ads.

*   **Your Threads information we collect if you use Threads without a profile**: We collect information necessary to provide the Threads experience without a profile, including your app, browser and device information (see ‘App, browser, and device information’ below) and **information about your activity on Threads**, including the types of content you view, the Threads features you use and how you use them, and the time, frequency, and duration of your activities on Threads.
*   **App, browser, and device information that we collect regardless of whether you use Threads with a profile or not**: We collect and receive information from and about the different devices you use and how you use them, as further described in the [Meta Privacy Policy](https://privacycenter.instagram.com/policy). Learn more about how we use cookies and similar technologies in the [Meta Cookies Policy](https://privacycenter.instagram.com/policies/cookies/).
*   **Information we collect from Third Party Services and Third Party Users**: We collect information about the Third Party Services and Third Party Users who interact with Threads. If you interact with Threads through a Third Party Service (such as by following Threads users, interacting with Threads content, or by allowing Threads users to follow you or interact with your content), we collect information about your third-party account and profile (such as your username, profile picture, and the name and IP address of the Third Party Service on which you are registered), your content (such as when you allow Threads users to follow, like, reshare, or have mentions in your posts), and your interactions (such as when you follow, like, reshare, or have mentions in Threads posts).

How do we use this information?
-------------------------------

**When you use Threads with a profile**, we use the Threads information we collect for Threads for the purposes described in the [Meta Privacy Policy](https://privacycenter.instagram.com/policy) under “How do we use your information?”, including:

*   to provide, personalise (including ads if we show you ads), and improve Threads,
*   to provide measurement, analytics and other business services,
*   to promote safety, integrity and security across Meta Products,
*   to communicate with you, and
*   to research and innovate for social good.

**If you have created a Threads profile with your Instagram account,** we also use the Threads information we collect to provide, personalise (including ads if we show you ads), and improve Instagram, and - if you have added your Instagram account to an [Accounts Center](https://help.instagram.com/1731078377046291/?helpref=faq_content) with other Meta Products - other Meta Products. Similarly, [your Instagram information is used on Threads](https://help.instagram.com/788669719351544?helpref=faq_content) to do things such as import your profile information, personalise your Threads and Instagram feeds, and help you stay safe on both apps.

**If you use Threads without a profile**, we will not use your Threads information with your Instagram account, and your Threads information won’t be used for ads. We use your Threads information to provide and improve Threads, and to promote safety, integrity, and security on Meta Products.

How is information shared?
--------------------------

In addition to sharing information in the ways described in the [Meta Privacy Policy](https://privacycenter.instagram.com/policy) under “How is your information shared on Meta Products or with integrated partners?”, “How do we share information with third parties?” and “How do the Meta Companies work together?”, Threads information is shared in the following ways **when you use Threads with a profile**:

*   **Public Information**: Like on Instagram, some of your information on Threads is always public and available to anyone, on or off Meta Products, including your username, name, profile picture, and bio. For content you share, you can set the audience by choosing between a private or public profile. With a private profile, only followers you approve can see and interact with the content you share. If your profile is public, anyone on or off Threads can see and interact with the content you share, including on Third Party Services (see below) and other Meta Products like Facebook. You can also restrict the audience for your content by blocking individual accounts from viewing them. Keep in mind that whether your profile is private or public, your username, name, profile picture, and bio remain public. Learn more about how you can [control your Threads profile privacy](https://help.instagram.com/225222310104065?helpref=faq_content).
*   **Sharing With Third-Party Services & Users**: Threads is integrated with Third Party Services via an interoperable protocol. This means that you can use Threads to share content with Third Party Users via their respective Third Party Service, such as by making your profile public or by approving followers from Third Party Services. It also means that you can interact with content and people from these Third Party Services, without having to leave Threads. When you interact with content or Third Party Users or otherwise make your content available to Third Party Services, e.g. by having a public profile, please be aware that you are directing us to deliver your information to services not controlled by Meta as necessary to integrate with the interoperable protocol, so that your information can be stored and processed by the Third Party Services, and be surfaced to their Third Party Users.
    
    *   For example, when you have a follower who is a Third Party User, we will share a copy of your post and your information to this follower’s Third Party Service so that it can store, process, and deliver the post to your follower. Similarly, if you make your profile public, a copy of your post and your information is made available to the applicable Third Party Service so that it can store and process that information.
    *   As another example, when you like or reply to a post from a Third Party Service, you are asking us to share a copy of that like or reply to the Third Party Service so that it can be stored, processed, and delivered to the user and appear along with the post. We’ll receive similar information from the Third Party Service so that you can see the post and its comments.
    *   The information we share with the Third Party Service will depend on your activity, but usually will include your profile information (such as your username, name, profile picture, and bio), and could also include things like the content of the comment, interaction, or post, including any attachments such as photos or videos; and certain metadata associated with your interaction, such as IP address of our Threads server and the timestamp of the interaction.
    
    Threads is interoperable with Third Party Services, so keep in mind that, because of Thread’s integration with Third Party Services, content you share is not limited to Meta and Threads users. Information sent to Third Party Services is no longer in Meta’s control and is subject to the terms and policies of those Third Party Services. People in your audience, including Third Party Users, can view your content and can choose to share it with others outside your audience.

Similarly, we **collect and process information from Third Party Services and Third Party Users** to show this information on Threads when Third Party Users interact with or allow interactions from Threads, e.g. by approving Threads users among their followers, replying or otherwise interacting with posts and content from Threads users, or by making information publicly available via their Third Party Service.

**If you use Threads without a profile**, we share your information in the ways described in the [Meta Privacy Policy](https://privacycenter.instagram.com/policy) under “How do we share information with third parties?” and “How do the Meta Companies work together?”.

What is our legal basis for processing your information and what are your rights?
---------------------------------------------------------------------------------

Threads is part of Instagram, and as such is a Meta Product. **When you use Threads with a profile**, we process the information as described above, including your Threads Profile Information, Threads Activity, Threads Followers and Other Connections, as described in the Meta Privacy Policy:

*   as necessary to fulfil the [Threads Terms of Use](https://help.instagram.com/769983657850450?helpref=faq_content) and the [Instagram Terms of Use](https://help.instagram.com/581066165581870?helpref=faq_content), including to provide the Threads experience and to enable interoperability with Third Party Services and Third Party Users (once Threads is interoperable with Third Party Services);
*   consistent with your consent, which you may revoke at any time;
*   as necessary to comply with our legal obligations;
*   to protect your vital interests, or those of others;
*   as necessary in the public interest; and
*   as necessary for our (or others') legitimate interests, unless those interests are overridden by your interests or fundamental rights and freedoms that require protection of personal data.

[Learn more](https://privacycenter.instagram.com/policy/?section_id=7-WhatIsOurLegal) about these legal bases and how they relate to the ways in which we process data.

**If you use Threads without a profile**, we process your information as necessary to perform our obligations under our contracts with you, particularly the [Threads Terms of Use](https://help.instagram.com/769983657850450?helpref=faq_content) and the [Instagram Terms of Use](https://help.instagram.com/581066165581870?helpref=faq_content), and as necessary to achieve our (or others') legitimate interests unless those interests are overridden by your interests or fundamental rights and freedoms that require protection of personal data. [Learn more](https://privacycenter.instagram.com/policy/?section_id=7-WhatIsOurLegal) about these legal bases and how they relate to the ways in which we process data.

**For Threads users under the age of majority** (under 18, in most applicable countries) who have a limited ability to enter into an enforceable contract only, where we may be unable to process your information on the grounds of contractual necessity as described above, we rely on our legitimate interests or the legitimate interests of a third party, where they are not outweighed by your interests or fundamental rights and freedoms. The categories of information we use, the legitimate interests relied on and why and how it’s processed are set out in the [Meta Privacy Policy](https://privacycenter.instagram.com/policy).

Exercising your rights
----------------------

We offer you a variety of tools to view, manage, download, and delete your Threads information by visiting your Threads Settings. You can also learn how to exercise your rights including how to access, correct, port, and delete your information by visiting our [Help Center](https://help.instagram.com/179980294969821?helpref=faq_content), your settings for Threads and Instagram, and your device-based settings. You can delete your Threads profile at any time. If you have created a Threads profile with your Instagram account, you can also delete your Threads profile by deleting your Instagram account. Learn more about [deleting your Threads profile](https://help.instagram.com/313703828012423?helpref=faq_content) in our Help Centre, and how to delete your Instagram account in the [Meta Privacy Policy](https://privacycenter.instagram.com/policy). You can also [contact Meta to exercise your rights](https://help.instagram.com/contact/1169130897068670).

**If you use Threads without a profile**, you can [contact Meta to exercise your rights](https://help.instagram.com/contact/1169130897068670).

How long do we keep your information?
-------------------------------------

We keep information as long as we need it to provide our Products, comply with legal obligations, or protect our or other's interests. We decide how long we need information on a case-by-case basis. Learn more about how we decide how long to keep information in [Meta’s Privacy Policy](https://privacycenter.instagram.com/policy/?section_id=8-HowLongDoWe).

Further information and how to contact Meta with questions
----------------------------------------------------------

The data controller responsible for your personal data is Meta Platforms Ireland Limited, which you can [contact online](https://help.instagram.com/contact/1169130897068670) or via the contact address below at:

Meta Platforms Ireland, Ltd

MERRION ROAD,

DUBLIN 4,

D04 X2K5,

IRELAND

FAO: Privacy Operations

ATTN: Privacy Operations

Contact the [Data Protection Officer](https://help.instagram.com/contact/1169130897068670) for Meta Platforms Ireland Limited.

You also have the right to lodge a complaint with Meta Platforms Ireland's lead supervisory authority, the Irish Data Protection Commission or your local supervisory authority.

Related Articles
----------------

Related Articles
